Pranav Raikote

COMPUTER VISION PRACTITIONER

Passionate researcher and practitioner in Deep Learning having 2+ years of experience in Computer Vision & allied domains. Seeking an opportunity to exhibit my skills and contribute to the organization with my expertise.

pranavraikote@gmail.com +91-9448210677 pranavraikote.github.io github.com/pranavraikote medium.com/@pranavraikote

EDUCATION

B.Tech - Computer Science & Engineering BMS Institute of Technology & Management

- Aug 2016 October 2020
- CGPA 7.62/10.0

Pre-University Education

KLE S Nijalingappa PU College

- Mar 2014 Mar 2016
- Percentage 70%

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Deep Learning Intern

DeepVisionTech.AI

- Aug 2020 Oct 2020
- Worked on Generative Adversarial Networks to generate realistic videos as part of dataset synthesis problem statement

Developer Intern

Simplifi Commerce

- Aug 2019 Oct 2019
- Implemented Proof of Concepts in Python, Image Processing and Deep Learning
- Worked on Full-Stack development in NodeJS as part of a website requirement

Machine Learning Consultant

Infidata Technologies

- Jul 2019 Aug 2019
- Worked as a Technical Consultant for various student led project teams guiding them in developing Machine Learning Solutions

POSITIONS OF RESPONSIBILITY

Chairperson IEEE Student Branch, BMSIT&MNov 2019 - Aug 2020

 Successfully led a team towards greater goals and sustained efforts throughout my tenure bringing a positive impact in our institution and beyond

IEEE R10 Students Activities Committee

Feb 2020 - Present

 Contributed in writing content being a part of the Media and Publicity Sub-Committee

SKILLS

- Python
- JAVA
- C Programming
- TensorFlow
- Cloud Computing
- Linux

PROJECTS

Diagnosis of COVID-19 from Chest X-RaysApr 2020 - Dec 2020

- Designed and developed a Deep Learning Ensemble Model which can give a diagnostic presence of Viral infection in a Chest X-Ray
- Extensive research on Image pre-processing, Model building and HPO techniques carried out and materialized using TensorFlow

Diagnosis of Pneumonia from Chest X-Rays Dec 2019 - Apr 2020

- Designed and developed a Deep Learning Model for a quick and state of the art results on diagnosis of Pneumonia in a Chest X-Ray
- Data cleaning,pre-processing per image basis was carried out and SOTA architectures were explored to improve on the current industry results. Stanford Medical Group's ChexPert data was used

Detection of Road Lanes from a Video Stream Apr 2020 - Apr 2020

- Developed an end-to-end Image processing pipeline for detecting lanes on road given a video input or live stream
- Various Image processing filters and techniques were used to arrive at the lane markers. Potential to be developed as a solution for custom fitting into cars for driving assistance

Image Caption Generator using LSTM & CNN Mar 2020 - Mar 2020

 Developed a Caption Generator which on given an input will generate multiple-word descriptions. Model was a combination of LSTM and a CNN

Intrepretation of Sign Language from a Video Jan 2020 - Mar 2020

 Used CNN and Image pre-processing techniques to build a Deep Learning model which on given an input video, will extract frames and output an inference sentence depicting the action

Extraction of Useful Information from Images July 2019 - Sep 2019

 Developed an automation application to extract valuable information given a pdf document. Tesseract OCR and MySQL DB were used for effective extraction and storage of results respectively

CERTIFICATIONS

Deep Learning Specialization (May 2019)

• 5 courses

Al in Medicine Specialization (May 2019)

• 3 courses

Tensorflow Specialization (Jun 2019)

• 4 courses